RG 069:024, William S. Goslee Papers
Connecticut State Library
William S. Goslee papers
1815-1892
Connecticut State Library
Goslee, William S., 1832-1892
Sumner, George O., 1800-1877
3.75 cubic feet
The papers consist of materials pertaining to William S. Goslee's legal and personal affairs. Goslee was a lawyer for the town of Glastonbury and was active in town politics, church and school issues.
RG069_024
T001394
Biographical Note
William S. Goslee was a lawyer for the town of Glastonbury, Connecticut. He was born on August 15, 1832 to James Goslee and Polly Sumner Goslee. He was the oldest of five children. During the Civil War he was drafted for service but due to some measure of deafness he did not serve. He attended school at the Glastonbury Academy but then continued his education for a brief time in the Williston Academy in East Hampton, Massachusetts, and Wesleyan Academy in Wilbraham, Massachusetts. He studied law under Judge Loren P. Waldo of Tolland, was admitted to the bar in 1857, and then returned to Glastonbury to establish a general law practice. He eventually became particularly interested in the branch of law pertaining to the powers and duties of the town. William Goslee handled mainly estates, foreclosures, war pension claims, and breach of contract cases. One of his most noted cases is Wethersfield v. Glastonbury, a dispute over town lines and taxation rights that went all the way to the Connecticut Supreme Court in 1873. He married Mary Teresa Storrs on October 30, 1861, and they had one child together, Henry Storrs Goslee on September 12, 1872.
William Goslee was also extremely active within the town of Glastonbury. He was on the Board of Trustees for the Glastonbury Academy, a secondary school. It is where he sent his own son, Henry Goslee, to school. William also served as Financial Trustee for the Church of Glastonbury from 1880 to around 1892. He also had a vested interest in politics. He became a clerk for the Connecticut House of Representatives in 1858 and was elected to the Connecticut State Senate in 1870.
William S Goslee was a man of vast literary tastes, and was reported to have one of the finest libraries in all of Glastonbury. He was also an amateur genealogist. It is possible that it was his Uncle George O. Sumner who got him interested in genealogy, but what is clear is that the two of them researched both the Goslee and Sumner family's genealogy throughout their lifetimes. George O. Sumner was a doctor, who lived in several Connecticut towns during his lifetime. He lived in Lyme, Groton, New Haven, and lastly Coventry until his death on November 24, 1877. As made obvious by his numerous revisions to his last Will and Testament, he was ill, off and on, for at least the latter 25 years of his life. Due to his illness, William S. Goslee helped him financially for the latter part of his life. Upon his death, William S. Goslee handled Sumner's estate.
At the time of Goslee's death he was in the mist of compiling a history of Glastonbury, but unfortunately the manuscript was lost. William S. Goslee died March 31, 1892 at his home in Glastonbury; he was survived by his wife and son.
Scope and Content
The collection is arranged into five series: Legal Papers, Personal Papers, Glastonbury Records, Genealogy, and Sumner's Personal Papers.
Series 1. Legal Papers, 1850-1892, contains records pertaining to Goslee's position as a lawyer. These records include any legal correspondence between him and his clients, war pension claims, and records of specific court cases, as well as journals of his notes on legal matters.
Series 2. Personal Papers, 1856-1892, contains records of a personal nature. These records include personal correspondence between friends and family, receipts, speeches and orations, political papers, published work, drawing and notes, and a record of the town of Suffield.
Series 3. Genealogy Papers, circa 1850-1890, contains records of the genealogy of the Goslee and Sumner families, as well as correspondence pertaining to their family's genealogy and that of others. Also included are locks of hair from several members of the Sumner family. There is a genealogy chart in an oversize folder.
Series 4. George O. Sumner Papers, 1815-1853, contains records from George O. Sumner, including personal correspondence and documentation regarding a case of slander, known as Sumner v. Utley. There are three newspapers, with legal notices regarding the case in an oversize folder.
Series 5. Glastonbury Records, 1821-1892, contains records of the town of Glastonbury. These papers include town records regarding censuses, its library, taxes, dog owners, and school district surveys. Also included are the records of the Glastonbury Academy and the Church of Glastonbury. The records of the Glastonbury Academy consist of term records, tuition receipts, and lists of library books. The bulk of the records from the Church of Glastonbury are receipts from 1880-1886.
Arrangement
Series 1. Legal Papers, 1850-1892, correspondence arranged chronologically; legal documents and war pension claims are arranged alphabetical by claimant; and cases arranged alphabetically by title.
Series 2. Personal Papers, 1856-1892, arranged chronologically.
Series 3. Genealogy Papers, circa 1850-1890, arranged chronologically.
Series 4. George O. Sumner Papers, 1815-1853, arranged chronologically.
Series 5. Glastonbury Records, 1821-1892, arranged chronologically.
Related Material
RG 069:083, Goslee Family Papers, 1795-1905, Connecticut State Library.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Connecticut -- Genealogy; Connecticut -- History -- 1775-1865; Connecticut. Superior Court; Lawyers; Legislators -- Connecticut; Connecticut -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950; Connecticut -- Politics and government -- 1775-1865; Glastonbury (Conn.: Town) -- History; Schools -- Connecticut -- Glastonbury (Town) -- History; Glastonbury Academy -- History; Glastonbury (Conn.: Town) -- Church history
Places:
Glastonbury (Conn.); New Haven (Conn.); Suffield (Conn.)
Persons:
Goslee, William S., 1832-1892; Sumner, George O., 1800-1877
Document Types:
Clippings; Commercial correspondence; Personal correspondence; Constitutions; Correspondence; Human hair; Journals; Minutes; Legal correspondence; Legal documents; Legal notices; Pamphlets; Financial records; Newspapers
Restrictions on Access
Oversize items are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Acquisition Information
The collection was received by an unknown donor around 1930.
Container List
- Series 1. Legal Papers, 1850-1892
  - Correspondence, 1850, 1852, 1873-1875, 1877-1880, 1876 January-1884 August (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Blank envelopes, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Notary Public certificate, 1889 January 25 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Receipts, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Journals of court cases, notes on witness statements, circa 1870-1885; 4 journals (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - East Hartford Toll Bridge case, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Estate of George O. Sumner, will & testament, family letters, 1850, 1852, 1873-1875, 1877-1880 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Legal agreements, A-C, G-H, K, M, O-P, R, T, W, 1863-1869, 1875-1879, 1884-1888, 1891, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Lex Lori contracts, 1883 June-1892 February (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Michael Vail v. Town of Glastonbury, 1877 July-1891 May, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - War Pension claims, B-C, G-H, K, M, O-P, R, T, W, 1883-1890, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - War Pension claims, blank forms, 1890, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Wethersfield v. Glastonbury, Connecticut Supreme Court case, 1861, 1870-1874, undated (Box 2, Folder 6-8)
  - Wethersfield v. Glastonbury, Connecticut Supreme Court Case, Goslee's court journals, 1872-1873; 2 journals (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Series 2. Personal Papers, 1856-1892
  - Correspondence, 1872-1892 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Speeches and orations, 1859, 1869, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Political papers: notices, surveys, letters, advertisements, and Constitution of Republican Party of Glastonbury, 1868, 1871, 1876, 1880, 1883-1884, 1889, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Receipts, 1856-1891 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Published works, 1861-1891, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Drawing, recipes, and notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Doings of Town Meeting Suffield relating to the 20th anniversary settlement of said town, 1869 October 4 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Series 3. Genealogy, circa 1850-1890
  - Genealogy of Goslee and Sumner family's, circa 1850-1890 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Genealogy correspondence, 1878 May-1890 November (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Family chart, undated (Box Oversized)
- Series 4. George O. Sumner's Papers, circa 1815-1853
  - Slander case, Sumner v. Utley, 1827-1832 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Personal papers: correspondence, poetry, programs, and cards, 1815-1853, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Legal notices in newspapers, 1828-1832 (Box Oversized)
- Series 5. Glastonbury Records, 1821-1892
  - Town records, 1821, 1874 January, 1879, 1880, undated; 2 folders (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
    Folders consist of records such as the Census of 1879; dog owners, 1880, Glastonbury Library, tax records, and school district survey of districts 1-8, and 12-18.
  - Glastonbury Academy, 1874-1881 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Glastonbury Academy, 1882-1885, 1888, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Glastonbury Church receipts, 1880-1886 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
  - Glastonbury Church documents, 1883-1885, 1890-1892, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Glastonbury Town records - Town Meeting Scroll, 1887 October 17 (Box 5, Folder 1)